[Music]
hello my name is Roman uh in this
session I'll be covering the new
features and enhancements we're
launching with business Central 2024
wave 1 in the areas of administration
and governance these features will make
your life easier when administrating
business Central environments in the
cloud as well as enable new scenarios I
have a jam-packed agenda with me today
I'll start with a feature that we have
shipped already in February which is the
ability to transfer environments from
one ENT tenant to another then I'll talk
about a small but important enhancement
to the ability to recover deleted
environments we're introducing a new
role
called the Dynamics 365 business Central
administrator as well as we will ship
new environment level partner access
controls for business
Central then I'll cover briefly the new
upsource app
previews and I will get to linking
business Central environments to Power
Platform environments which will bring
me to the next section in governance
because that will allow us to
enable customer lockbox and customer
manage encryption keys and then I'll
wrap up with the new auditing
capabilities that we are going to ship
soon in perview so let's get right into
it this has been one of the most highly
anticipated features actually
transferring environments from one ENT
tenant to another and this is useful for
example when
consolidating tenants in a merger an
acquisition scenario or when for example
preparing environments for demo
purposes and then transferring them to a
customer
tenant and since we made this capability
available as a a self-service
functionality in the admin Center at the
beginning of February we have already
seen a few hundred environment transfers
so this is really cool let me show you
how it works so I'm here in the admin
Center and we wanted to make this as
easy as
possible we added this new button here
on top environment transfers and from
here you'll be able to transfer
environments out from this tenant to
another you will re be able to receive
environments and you will see if there's
any pending outgoing
transfers so to transfer an environment
out of this tenant into another very
simple you can select the environment to
transfer specify the destination ENT
attendant
ID and you can select the date and time
when the transfer should
happen for example I can pick here on
Friday in the evening 6:00 p.m.
6:30 so I'm not going to do that
transfer now but I'll show you how it on
the other side so to receive an
environment you specify the source
tenant uh pasted here and then you will
see the list of environments you can
accept there's a few things I would like
to point out with these features some
things good to know so very important
transfers can only be executed by
internal administrators this is for
security reasons and we want to be sure
that the user that is doing this
operation is authorized to do
so the requests that are sent from The
Source tenant to the destination tenant
have to be accepted on the destination
tenant within 8 hours and we do this to
avoid any hanging uh requests there
often you may want to plan for these
environment transfers in advance so we
allow you to schedule these transfers up
to 14 days in the future
and then very important after the
transfer there are some management tasks
that you need to do specifically when it
comes to the users so this is a
different tenant and you have to
recreate the users in the destination
tenant and also make sure to reassign
any permissions to these users again so
that it will work in the same way in the
new tenant as before of course the
destination tenant must have a paid
business Central license as well and
also available environment
quot and we do show the operations both
in the source tenant and the destination
tenant in the operations log in the
admin Center and you will also see these
transfer operations in the environment
Telemetry I mentioned it already before
a small and important Improvement when
it comes to recovering deleted
environments so since we launched this
feature we have avoided hundreds of
potentially painful accidents and
support requests and recently we have
improved it and doubled the recovery
period from 7 to 14 days to give some
extra time some more flexibility in case
things go wrong and important to know
also here is that this doesn't change
the total backup time that we have for
your data we still keep 28 days of
backup for all data the Dynamics 365
business Central administrator is a new
role that we have recently introduced
for users to administer and manage
business Central environments
essentially it's all the permissions
that are needed to access a business
Central environment to manage it perform
Administration
operations um access the admin Center
life cycle operations extension updates
and so on and very important it does not
give access to any other Dynamics 365
products also here a few things good to
know um the global administrator and
Dynamics 365 administrator roles that we
have been using for now will still
remain
supported but we will remove access to
help Des
administrators in the
future and then if you need additional
roles or permissions do request those
additional roles for example for Power
Platform service support administrator
or message center reader and the
different permissions and roles that you
may need on top of of the business
Central administrator role it's quite
common for larger implementations and
multi-site implementations to have
different partners working for the same
customer for example an Italian partner
working with an Italian environment and
then a partner in the US taking care of
the US environment for that same
International customer and to keep those
separate we are going to introduce
environment access and administration on
Partner level so that in the example
above the Italian partner would only be
able to administer and see the Italian
environment and the US partner would
only be able to do that for the US
environment there's a couple of things
that I would like to point out here
so this functionality will restrict both
the access to the environment and it
will also
restrict the ability to view modify and
delete the environment so it would not
show up if you don't have that access to
the
environment it also means that the
access is is going to be restricted both
for delegated users and also the entra
apps when using service
authentication and multiple partners can
be assigned per
environment the publisher of an
appsource app may run a preview for a
future version of an already public app
or a new app preview versions can then
be installed using a special URL
including the preview key parameter that
is provided by the app publisher in a
sandbox
environment this preview key can be set
or generated when uploading the apps on
Partner
Center when you have the preview key you
can install the app using this special
URL so it's business Central
dynamics.com you need to pass the tenant
ID and then filter on the app ID and
pass the preview key and that will
install the preview app in the
environment there's a few things also I
would like to share here that are good
to know so preview apps can only be
installed on Sandbox
environments if you have a Sandbox
environment with a preview version often
up
installed that environment cannot be
copied or restored to a production
environment previews can be updated to a
higher preview version or a public
version and then to install a new
preview version use the same install
link with the preview key or if you want
to install a new public version you can
do that from the admin
Center
and depending on how the environment is
configured when it comes to automatic
app
updates the installed preview apps will
also automatically be updated to higher
public versions with the minor or major
release of business
Central and also the installation of
preview apps can be traced in
Telemetry and that brings me to my next
topic the linking of business Central
environments to Power Platform
environments and that will allow us to
inherit selected data governance setting
from the Power Platform and apply them
to business Central
environments on the other hand it will
also provide a default Target
environment for integration features
from business Central into Power
Platform and data
verse so there's a couple of things also
good to know so the linking of
environments is one to one one business
Central environment to one Power
Platform environment and it can also be
reverted so unlinking is possible and
unlinking then disables the settings
that are inherited from the Power
Platform
environment but it would not remove any
Integrations that are deployed to the
Power Platform
environment the environment type and the
Azure Geo must match so sandbox to
sandbox production to production and it
needs to be in the same Azure
GE some selected environment operations
are blocked while that link exists for
example the environment cannot be
deleted so to be able to delete it you
need to unlink and then you can
proceed if you copy or restore an
environment that has a link it will not
inherit that link from The Source
because it's a one-on-one linking
relationship and then all
operations from the Power Platform for
environment side are
blocked finally small comment when
linking an environment it will trigger a
restart of the business Central
environment so once we have established
the link between the Power Platform
environment and the business Central
environment it will bring me to the next
section the governance part of it
because that enables two Enterprise
policies that we now can also apply
to business Central environments so the
first one is customer
lockbox so most
operations support troubleshooting that
is performed by
Microsoft does not require any access to
customer
data in some rare
occasions when we do need to access
customer data for example in response to
a support request customer lockbox is a
way is an interface face for customers
to review and approve or reject any
accesses to their customer
data the lockbox policy is enabled from
the Power Platform admin Center by
global administrators and Power Platform
administrators and then when Microsoft
attempts to access customer data in
business
Central the customer will receive a
lockbox request for review and then they
need to approve
it uh before Microsoft can access
customer data also here a couple of
things that are important to know the
lockbox policy is only enforced for
environments that are activated for
managed
environments it can be administered by
global administrators and Power Platform
administrators and there are some
certain Microsoft 365 and Power Platform
licensing requirements as well to enable
this and then once a lockbox request has
been
approved it is valid always for 8 hours
and then it will expire later in this
wave we will be shipping the support for
customer managed encryption Keys all
customer data that is stored in business
Central is encrypted addressed with a
strong Microsoft managed encryption key
by
default so Microsoft stores and manages
the database encryption key for all your
data so that you don't have
to however we will provide the ability
to use a customer managed encryption key
also referred to as cmk for your added
data protection control where you can
then self-manage the encryption key that
is associated with your business Central
environment
so this is a heads up that this will be
coming later in this wave and for more
details about the timeline I'd like to
refer you to the release
plan there's a few things also here good
to know the steps are essentially those
three to set it up first you create the
encryption key in your key Vault you
create an Enterprise policy and granted
access to that key
Vault and then in the Power Platform
admin Center you
apply this Enterprise policy to an
environment and in this way you can
manage the encryption of your
environments it requires
also a linked Power Platform managed
environment therefore there are similar
Microsoft 365 and Power Platform
licensing requirements and it can be
administered by global admin
administrators Dynamics 365
administrators and Power Platform
administrators and that will bring me to
my last topic for
today auditing and purview so the
primary purpose and reason here is to be
able to respond to for example security
events forensic
investigation and compliance obligations
having that unified audit log in
Microsoft prview in this initial release
we will
deliver the capability to audit create
update and delete events in business
Central that require administrator
privileges for example these are the
environment Administration operations
that you would do from the tenant admin
Center or extension configuration
installing updating or removing an
extension in the environment for example
user administr
and other in product Administration
operations as
well by default uh there's an 180 days
log retention in perview and it can be
extended up to 10 years with additional
add-on licenses and then to see the
audit logs you can either run manual
reports in the pview portal use
Powershell or the management activity
API to also automate and any events uh
or or processing that that you may want
to do Microsoft purview is included with
the Microsoft 365 license
types we have a bunch of resources
available if you want to learn more for
example join us on Yammer or Viva engage
we have an active group there and we'll
be very happy to answer your questions
and help out or join us for the live Q&A
on April 9 and 10 for any other
questions you may
have thank you
that's
it